<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>DeeKras.com</title><link href="http://www.deekras.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.deekras.com/feeds/about.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.deekras.com/</id><updated>2014-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>About my Blog</title><link href="http://www.deekras.com/about-my-blog.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dee Kras</name></author><id>tag:www.deekras.com,2014-12-09:about-my-blog.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h4&gt;So here's a little about me and this blog.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm fairly new to formal programming. In the past, I had dabbled in Access and Excel and played with VBA and SQL.  I always loved the logic of it.  But recently, I decided to jump fully into programming. I found a great mentor and was advised to start with Python. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got a few books and was directed to some awesome websites and of course the Python docs. And then got started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of those resources were great.  And some were more confusing than useful - at least to me.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then, I had the most wonderful opportunity to be accepted to the Hacker School program in Fall 2014. On the &lt;a href="https://www.hackerschool.com/"&gt;Hacker School website&lt;/a&gt;, they call it a 'retreat for programmers', and it was. For 12 weeks, I was fully immersed in programming - with great facilitators and mentors who assisted and guided me through the many questions I had.  I also got to work with fellow Hacker Schoolers in peer programming. And there were lots of break out discussions and workshops and resources.  I will probably write more about the Hacker School experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this blog is about sharing some of those discussions - so that someone else may benefit.  I will write my blog in the way that I learned. Lots of practical application of the many different methods and libraries and all. With lots of explanations of what the code means and links for further reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm always learning, so your comments are helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dee Kras&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;early winter 2014&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>